

Sneha Giri

Kolkata 9748479372 • sneha.giri@gmail.com

Objective

Management & Sales Trainer with rich experience in Talent management, Quality, Goverance and Audit. In my 8+ career I have been analysing and interpreting data which highlights the focus area and accordingly working upon the same which helps the organisation (stakeholders) to enhance the talent, productivity & revenue and quality of working standards are also improved by regular interventions and management via training and audit.

Work Experience

Assistant Manager - L&D TalentDeloitte USI

April 2023 - Till date

- Engage with the business to understand business drivers and objectives, and then translate that into Learning required to ensure that we have a workforce fit for the future and provide our team the ability to deliver quality services for our clients
- Conduct learning needs analysis across client groups and implementing appropriate development interventions; work with business units and teams to determine learning plans and key learning objectives and bespoke business unit learning interventions
- Provide strategic advice to the business to assist it in meeting its capability uplift objectives
- Proactively advise the business stakeholder on learning solutions and pedagogical aspects, engaging the Learning community as appropriate
- Work with SMEs to ensure learning is aligned to intelligent technology strategy to have a ready workforce that can meet / exceed customer needs and to ensure we can win / bid on work
- Drive the development & delivery of formal & informal learning solutions, managing the business case, budget, stakeholder relationships (business and learning team), deployment, tracking and evaluation
- Work closely with the HRBPs, program delivery teams and resourcing refine the program nomination process to ensure that the right people are attending the right training
- Provide regular review/update of career learning journeys based on input from business to keep current
- Provide monthly scorecard reporting to review L&D investment/activity

- and business impact
- Help develop and manage the annual L&D budget, including forecasting, for the business unit
- Responsible for understanding the overall catalogue of offerings available.
- Will be able to work on the complete End to End Learning solution for their capability / practice which includes: Identifying, designing and curating learning and meeting objectives.
- Tracks each learning solution within the learning map/curricula from development through to deployment to retirement
- Reports back over the overall learning map/curriculum status (monthly and quarterly) and the business impact measures agreed with the business
- General coordination and management of L&D schedule including: program scheduling, room bookings, F&B ordering, printing materials, assist team members with queries, liaise with facilitators on requirements, manage program budgets, build and send learning communications, maintain the L&D calendar, arrange course set-up with L&D team member

Regional Training Manager

July 2022 - April 2023

Aditya Birla Capital

- Conduct instructional research and analysis on learners and contexts
- Developed surveys to identify the training needs based on projected production processes and changes as per the allocated materials and budget assigned
- Designing, developing and implementing training that are delivered online, facilitator based or in combination of the two as suggested by the stakeholders.
- Creating assessment questions and strategies.
- Evaluation of training programmes and making improvements based on the recommendations from the participants and stakeholders
- Train and create an impact on the future leaders of the organisation to encourage them to perform better
- Assess and develop the learning road map for the employees and help them to execute them in their work
- Strategise and resolve the issues and conflicts between the employees and create a productive team
- Develop and train my team of consultant trainers which helps them to understand their goals and skills required for their current role

Manager Training & Business Competency Development

Exide Life Insurance

Oct 2021-July 2022

- Designing, developing and implementing training that are delivered online, facilitator based or in combination of the two.
- Creating assessment questions and strategies.
- Evaluation of training programmes and making improvements based on the recommendations
- Train and create an impact on the future leaders of the organisation to

- encourage them to perform better
- Assess and develop the learning road map for the employees and help them to execute them in their work
- Strategise and resolve the issues and conflicts between the employees and create a productive team
- Each training was designed as per the need and budget allocated by the organisation under my supervision for East

Regional Service and Quality Manager

Dec 2018 - Oct 2021

Reliance Nippon Life Insurance Co. Ltd.

- Conduct instructional research and analysis on learners and contexts
- Developed surveys to identify the training needs based on projected production processes and changes which are implemented as per the budget allocated by the organisation
- Encourage and reinforcement of the rules and regulations set by the organisation to be followed by all level and departments which will help in minimising the efforts and increasing the productivity
- Provide exercises and activities that enhance the learning process
- Multi-location travelling to ensure the process is being followed specially to the loss making branches and guide them on improving their productivity and control the cost until they are profitable for the organisation and to implement a review mechanism on all levels to ensure the impact
- Training and leading the entire new sales force of the region to acknowledge them about the industry, organisation and work culture. Also to develop the required acumen to increase the productivity
- To study and improve the process and strategy to increase productivity and improve the profitability of the stakeholders
- Had the opportunity to guide and coach a team more than 20 successful sales managers as per the design of the role, first six month's of their performance and growth was my responsibility
- Joined as Territory Manager and promoted to the current designation in 2021

Asst. Manager Learning & Development September 2017 - November 2018 Max Skill First

- Sales training of the agency through various sessions specially designed for them which will help in improving the productivity and achieving the targets assigned
- Supervise the sales manager and his team to understand the situation and guide them by various tasks to ensure profitable business
- Enhance the business opportunity by monitoring and informing the agents upon their performance and inputs to improve their productivity and client base
- SWOT analysis of the agency and the stakeholders in order to improve their performance and beat the best
- Had to take care of the end to end training program and follow the budget

HR Manager

November 2015 - September 2017

DMT Consulting Pvt. Ltd.

- Assist the directors with various assignments and develop strategies which will help in developing the business
- Travel plans to be discussed and managed for various assignments to ensure the safety and security of our employees
- Screening, sourcing and recruiting from campus and allocate them to project work based on their interest
- Train and supervise to new employees ensuring they maintain fastidious attention to details
- Maintaining leaves and frame policies of the organisation from time to time
- Adhered to departmental controls and regulations maintain ethical conduct all the time
- Guest relationship management including the event management for the organisation

Education

XLRI, Jamshedpur

2017-2018

PGCBM in Business Management

• Executive MBA in Business Management

B.Com (Accountancy)

2008-2011

Calcutta University

Graduation

Other Activities

• Learning new skills to develop professionally and personally I enjoy sport, traveling, listening to music and sharing a great meal with friends.